<!DOCTYPE html>

<html lang="en">

	<head>
		<meta charset="UTF-8"/>
		<link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="styles/style.css"/>
		<meta name="author" content="Jake Chieng"/>
		<meta name="description" content="Enhancement page for PHP and MySQL"/>
		<meta name="keywords" content="Enhancement, PHP, MySQL"/>
		<script src="script/script.js"></script>
		<script src="script/enhancement.js"></script>
		<title>Enhancement for PHP and MySQL</title>
	</head>
	
	<body>
		
		<?php include_once("page_header.php");?>
	
		<?php include_once("page_menu.php");?>
		
		<article class="container">
			<h1>Enhancement</h1>
			<section>
				<h2><a target="_blank" href="view_users.php">User Management Module</a></h2>
				<p>To allow business owner / operator / web site administrator to manage the website easily, 
				a separate management website was made. One of the modules included in the website is the user management
				module that allows only the master account <strong>(username: owner, password: cwaphpsql)</strong> can access.
				This is to prevent unwanted entry into the module and easier management.</p>
				<p>In this user management module, more management accounts can be created to access other modules. This simplify
				user management as accounts can only be made by the master account. There is a list of user accounts in this module too.
				Changing password and deleting accounts are also possible in this module.
				To access the user management module (and also other management modules), the user needs to be logged in via the login page.
				This management module is <em>especially made for authorized personnels only</em>, so public users should not be able to access.</p>
				<p>For the implementation, a userTable is created to store accounts information such as username, password and privilege.
				Then, the master account information is stored inside it. The login system and the editing, creating and deleting use 
				the prepare statements in the query. To check the password, password_verify is used. The password stored is also 
				encrypted with hashed. Authentication is basically referring to userTable to check whether the username exists and whether
				the password matches. All the management modules, without login is unaccessible as log in status is checked. As long as
				the account is logged out via log out page, public user should not be able to access to these modules.</p>
				<p>Pages for this enhancement:</p>
				<ul>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="login_php">Login Page</a></p></li>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="edit_user.php">Edit User</a></p></li>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="create_user.php">Create User</a></p></li>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="edit_user.php">Edit User - Changing Password</a></p></li>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="delete_user.php">Delete User</a></p></li>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="delete_enquiry.php">Delete Enquiry</a></p></li>
				</ul>
				<p>References:</p>
				<ul>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.tutorialrepublic.com/php-tutorial/php-mysql-login-system.php">PHP MySQL Login System</a></p></li>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.php.net/manual/en/function.password-verify.php">password_verify</a></p></li>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.w3schools.com/php/php_mysql_select.asp">PHP MySQL Select Data</a></p></li>
				</ul>
			</section>
			
			<section>
				<h2><a target="_blank" href="view_products.php">Product Management Module</a></h2>
				<p>The other management module included is the product management module. This module can be accessed by accounts created, unlike the user module.
				From this module, products displayed can be viewed, created, edited or deleted as needed. However, only description, status and price can be
				edited. The product pages also retrieved information from the table to display to public users.</p>
				<p>To implement this module, a productTable is created in the database from the server to store the product information. In product pages, 
				the data is retrieved as needed to display. PHP MySQL is useful to retrieve, store and remove information for easier management.</p>
				<p>Pages for this enhancement:</p>
				<ul>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="login_php">Login Page</a></p></li>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="edit_product.php">Edit Product</a></p></li>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="create_product.php">Create New Product</a></p></li>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="delete_product.php">Delete Product</a></p></li>
				</ul>
				<p>References:</p>
				<ul>
					<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.w3schools.com/php/php_mysql_select.asp">PHP MySQL Select Data</a></p></li>
				</ul>
			</section>
		</article>
		
		<?php include_once("page_footer.php");?>
		
	</body>
</html>